Ananth Kalyanasundaram

Phone number: $+91-8056074660 \diamond LinkedIn profile$

Address: Flat No.7, Raga Sriniketan Apts., 41/51, RK Shanmugam Salai, KK Nagar, Chennai-600078, India ananth.kalyanasundaram@gmail.com AnanthK1998.github.io

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests broadly lie in the field of Computer Vision and Deep Learning. I am interested in developing novel algorithms that optimize feature representations in a deep neural network. I am also interested in working toward problems in 3D vision, segmentation and super-resolution.

EDUCATION

SRM Institute of Science and Technology

July 2016 - June 2020 Chennai, India

B. Tech (Computer Science and Engineering)

Percentage: 87.35/100

PUBLICATIONS

- · MRI Super-resolution using Laplacian Convolutional Neural Networks with Isotropic Undecimated Wavelet Loss. S.Ramanarayanan, B.Murugesan, A.Kalyanasundaram, S.Prabhakaran, S.Patil, M.Sivaprakasam. 42nd Annual International Conference of the IEEE Engineering in Medicine and Biology Society 2020 (EMBC 2020).
- · Detection of Pathological Myopia using Convolutional Neural Networks. A.Kalyanasundaram, S. Prabhakaran, Briskilal. J., Senthil Kumar. D. International Journal of Psychosocial Rehabilitation, Vol. 24, Issue 05, 2020

WORK EXPERIENCE

Human Analysis Lab, Michigan State University

September 2020 - Present

Research Intern

East Lansing, Michigan, USA

Currently working on minimizing dimensionality of feature representations obtained from the layers of deep neural networks under the supervision of Professor Vishnu Boddeti.

KPMG India July 2020 - Present Mumbai, India

Data Analyst Intern

· Worked on optimizing tax processes after analysis of data for the Tax Technology and Transformation

- · Created automation software for OTP verification in websites.
- · Tested several bots and ensured high quality output was produced.

Dept. of Translational Medicine and Research, SRM Medical College August 2019 - June 2020

Research Intern Chennai, India

- · Analyzed and cleaned real-life Knee MRI data. Used image processing techniques to make the data trainable.
- · Developed a novel loss function for this task which delivered better results and published a paper on the same at the IEEE EMBC 2020 conference.

Healthcare Technology Innovation Centre(HTIC), IIT-Madras

May 2018 - July 2019 Chennai, India

Research Intern

- · Implemented several state-of-the-art deep learning architectures for the task of Image Segmentation and Classification.
- · Achieved a position in the top 20 of the leaderboard at the time of conclusion of challenges held by ISBI and SPIE Medical Imaging conferences.
- · Conducted research using different architectures for the task of Super-resolution on Brain MRI.

PROJECTS

Cancer Cellularity Prediction System

December 2018 - March 2019

The challenge was to predict cancer cellularity given an image of a tissue. Achieved a position of 6 out of 100 teams at the time of conclusion, with a prediction probability of 0.88 using an ensemble of ResNet architectures. Developed a user interface for the same using Kivy.

Salt Segmentation for detection of Petroleum under Rocks

July 2018 - December 2018

Worked on the project as part of a challenge on Kaggle. The task was to segment salt regions in images of rock surfaces. Achieved a dice score of 0.83 on the dataset using a UNet with ResNet34 encoder and data augmentation techniques.

Histopathic Segmentation of Nuclei using Deep Learning

May 2018 - June 2018

This challenge was held as part of the MICCAI 2018 conference. Trained with the UNet architecture after applying extensive data augmentation techniques. Achieved a dice score of 0.82 on the test set.

Cyclone Prediction using Machine Learning

March 2018 - April 2018

Worked on the HURDAT dataset released by the NHC for classification of weather phenomena. Cleaned the data and achieved an F1-score of 0.843 on the validation set, using supervised learning techniques.

COURSES

University Courses

- · Machine Learning
- · Artificial Intelligence
- · Probability and Queuing Theory
- · Advanced Calculus and Complex Analysis
- · Data Science and Big Data Analytics

Online Courses

- · Machine Learning by Stanford University, Coursera
- · Deep Learning Specialization by Andrew Ng
- · Python for Everybody, Coursera
- · Deep Neural Networks with PyTorch by IBM, Coursera
- · AI Capstone Project with Deep Learning by IBM, Coursera

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Skills: Machine Learning, Computer Vision

Languages: Python, C++, MATLAB

Frameworks: Tensorflow, Pytorch, Keras, OpenCV